And so you say, what about the brain? I mean we're engineers right. We want to build something.
we want to build something that's intelligent. It'd be a little silly to ignore the fact that we
actually have a working prototype, and we're
trying to do this really hard thing. We
should look at the prototype.
And you know human minds are not perfect
decision-makers, but by and large they are
actually very good.
And even the cases where humans are
famously not rational, there are many cases
there where you can actually say, well
they are rational if you think of their
goals in a different way. That's a whole
sticky subject, we'lll talk about that
later in the course. But basically human
brains are in many ways
better than what we can build.
So let's just reverse engineer them. So it
turns out, brains aren't as modular as software, and
they're a whole lot more squishy. And
so they're hard to reverse engineer.
And because we can't reverse engineer
them we have a very limited understanding of
what brains actually do, we really
don't
kind of reverse engineer them and build a kind of
biomimetic brain.
And in particular there is an idea, which,
you know, this is one point of view,
but I think it's got a lot of merit to it.
People say that brains are to
intelligence as wings are to flight.
That is to say, that
the biggest breakthrough in manned
flight--does anybody know what was the
biggest breakthrough in manned flight?
Stop making the wings flap, right.
Stop trying to make a really big bird
made out of metal or something, or fabric
right. And so this idea of, okay, maybe the
wings can be fixed 'cause we're going to be
going faster or we're going to be going higher,
it's going to be rigid. And so when people started
thinking, okay, we're going to learn something about
aerodynamics from the proofs of concept, say
the birds, but we're not gonna just
slavishly mimic what's in the biology.
Same thing with the brains. We're gonna
learn what we can, but we're not gonna just
mimic that because we got different constraints
and a limited understanding of what
the brain does to begin with.
So, what do we actually get. Well, we do know
something from the brain and it boils down
to this, kind of at the very highest
level.
We know that in order to make good
decisions,
there's really two parts to that.
One way you can make a good decision
is by remembering that in the past you
did this thing and it was bad,
so you know not to do that thing again.
You know that boils down to memory. That leads into
learning, machine learning, and that's
going to be a big part of this course.
The other way you can make a good
prediction, is through simulation--having a
model of the world. We think, alright, what
would happen if I do this, well then this
would happen, then this would happen--oh,
and then that would happen,
that would be bad. And so you can realize
that something is a bad decision by thinking
through a chain of consequences. Not
actually doing that chain,
but thinking it through in a simulated model of the
world
and that's going to occupy the first half of
the class, when we think about
what it means to have a model of the world, that's an abstraction
of the world,
and what it means to think ahead along a kind of tree of outcomes.